<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<news>
	<article lang="de-DE">
		<title>"Ich wollte mich zu Hause verkriechen"</title>
		<pubdate>17-11-2016</pubdate>
		<body>
			Hillary Clinton hat das erste Mal über die Zeit nach ihrer Wahlniederlage gesprochen. Sie sei schwer enttäuscht gewesen und habe sich am liebsten zu Hause verkriechen wollen. Das Wahlergebnis zeige aber auch eine tiefe Spaltung in der US-Bevölkerung. Bei ihrem ersten öffentlichen Auftritt nach dem Eingeständnis ihrer Wahlniederlage gegen Donald Trump hat Hillary Clinton sich zutiefst enttäuscht über das Ergebnis der US-Präsidentschaftswahl gezeigt. Seit der Wahl vor gut einer Woche fragten sich viele Menschen, ob die USA "das Land sind, für das wir sie gehalten haben", sagte die unterlegene Kandidatin der Demokratischen Partei bei einer Benefizveranstaltung in Washington.
		</body>
	</article>
	<article lang="nl-NL">
		<title>Premier Canada onder vuur over toezegging aan Trump</title>
		<pubdate>16-11-2016</pubdate>
		<body>
			De Canadese premier Justin Trudeau is onder vuur komen te liggen, omdat hij Donald Trump heeft gezegd bereid te zijn het vrijhandelsakkoord NAFTA te veranderen. Zowel de oppositie als partijgenoten hebben Trudeaus 'slappe houding' fel bekritiseerd. Trudeau zou naïef zijn en paniekerig hebben gereageerd op de keuze van de Amerikaanse kiezers voor de populist Trump als nieuwe president van de VS. De protectionist Trump heeft in zijn campagne vrijhandelsakkoorden afgekraakt als duistere afspraken die de VS geld en banen kosten. Het Noord-Amerikaanse Vrijhandelsakkoord (NAFTA) is al sinds 1994 in werking en is gesloten tussen Canada, Mexico en de VS.
		</body>
	</article>
	<article lang="en-GB">
		<title>Nicola Sturgeon warned of hard border with England if she pushes Norway-style EU deal</title>
		<pubdate>15-11-2016</pubdate>
		<body>
			Tories and experts poured scorn on suggestions Scotland could pursue membership of the European Economic Area (EEA) in the wake of Brexit. Reports suggested ministers have privately floated the so-called Norway model as they seek to maintain links with the bloc. Even if Nicola Sturgeon’s government secures the backing of the UK, EU and EEA critics argued this could see border restrictions with the rest of the UK - where most of the country’s exports are sold. The row flared as Nationalists failed to secure cross-party backing for its bid to maintain Scotland’s place in the single market if UK ministers “cannot or will not secure that option”. Economy Secretary Keith Brown had urged rivals to rally behind a motion calling for this to be “fully protected”. But the administration had to rely on pro-independence Greens for support after Labour abstained and Tories and Lib Dems voted against the SNP motion. During Holyrood’s eleventh debate on the issue critics accused the SNP using Brexit as a “thinly veiled” attempt to pursue their campaign to break-up Britain.
		</body>
	</article>		
</news>
